# **Yared Gari**

💌 yaredbacha@gmail.com 📞 2066410154 👂 Atlanat, GA 🛚 in Linkedin 🜎 GitHub 🔭 Portfolio

# Summary

Proactive and multidisciplinary Software Engineer with experience in web development and data analytics. With around 3 years of experience as a software developer and 8 years as a university instructor. Passionate about learning new technologies and staying up-to-date with industry trends to deliver value added products. Seeking a Software developer position to contribute to company's goals and push the boundaries of technology.

# **Professional Experience**

**Software Engineer,** *Mckinsey & Company* 03/2022 – present | Atlanata, US

- Collaborated on the development of the McKinsey
   Quarterly Digital edition and McKinsey Insight store,
   which added over 5k of new users to our user base
   in the first month alone.
- Implemented unit and integration test suites that resulted in a drastic decrease in production issues.
- Identified, debugged, tested, and resolved various issues within our codebase to improve the overall quality of our application.
- Conducted A/B experiments using Adobe Analytics with my team to optimize Mckinsey.com, identifying opportunities that increased our user acquisition rate by more than 20%..

**Junior software Engineer,** *Axious Solutions* 

12/2020 - 03/2022 | Washington DC, US

- Collaborated with senior engineers on bug fixing, feature development and testing.
- Attended training and development sessions.

**Lecturer and Visiting Researcher,** Bahir Dar

University, University of Calgary & Wisconsin-madison 06/2012 – 12/2020

Bahir Dar, Calgary, Madison | ETH, US

- Taught hydraulic structure I and II courses
- Published two research articles on international iournals
- Supervised 3 batches of undergraduate students.

#### **Skills**

JavaScript, React, React Native, Redux, Next js,
Typescript, jQuery, Tailwind, React Testing library,
jest, unit and integration testing, Accessibility,
Responsive design, Git, GitHub, Bootstrap,
Webpack, Figma, HTML5/XML/JSON, CSS3/SCSS, AB
test/adobe analytics, code debugging, agile/Scrum
Frontend Skills

Node, Express, Sequelize ORM, REST API, GraphQL, Docker, AWS, CI/CD, SQL, MYSQL, Mongo DB Backend Skills

communication, team work, growth mindset, problem solving, attension to details, time management, persistance and protectiveness Soft skills

# **Certificates**

- AWS cloud practitioner
- Certified Javascript developer
- React framework Nano degree

#### Education

#### Full Stack developer,

Multiverse Bootcamp (15 months) 2022 | NY, US

# Java Full Stack developer,

Atlanta Technical College/Generation USA (6 months) 2021 | Atlanta, US

### Masters In Hydraulic Engineering,

Bahir Dar Institute of Technology 2011 – 2012 | Bahir Dar, Ethiopia

# **Bachelor in Water Resource Engineering,**

Bahir Dar University 2005 – 2009 | Bahir Dar, Ethiopia

# **Publications**

link ♂